어둑한 점은 용서하게.
Excuse the gloom,
이 만남은 아무도 알아선 안 되니.
but none may know of this meeting.
내 고민의 본질은 이보다 더 어둡다.
The nature of my trouble is darker still.
일 년도 더 전에, 대거폴의 리산더스 왕은
Over a year ago, King Lysandus of Daggerfall
전장에서 명예롭게 전사했네.
died honorably on the field of battle.
그는 그대만큼이나 충성스러운 신하이자,
He was as loyal a subject,
동맹이며 친구였지...
ally and friend... as you are.
나는 진심으로 그를 애도했네.
I did grieve for him,
하지만 그의 영혼은 안식하지 못하고 있다.
But his spirit does not rest.
유령 군대를 이끌고 옛 왕국을 떠돌며,
With the spectral army, he haunts his former kingdom,
복수를 외치고 있지!
crying for revenge!
선량하고 충성스러운 자가 어째서 그런 저주를 받았는지 모르겠네.
I do not know why a good and loyal man would be so cursed.
어쩌면 그대가 답을 찾아
Perhaps you can find the answer
오블리비언의 대리석 아가리를 닫고,
and close the marble jaws of Oblivion,
그의 영혼에 평안을 안겨 줄 수 있을지도 모르지.
bringing peace to his soul.
황제로서,
I ask this as your Emperor
또 친구로서 그대에게 부탁하네.
and as your friend.
그보다 덜 중대한 부탁도 하나 있네.
I have one lesser request.
몇 해 전, 나는
Several years ago, I wrote a letter
대거폴의 왕비에게 편지 한 통을 보냈네.
to the Queen of Daggerfall.
하지만 그 편지는 도착하지 않았지.
It never arrived.
그 편지는 감상적이고...
The letter was of a sentimental and...
개인적인 내용이었네.
personal nature.
그 편지를 찾아 파기해 준다면,
If you find and destroy that letter,
고맙게 여기겠네.
I will be grateful.
이제 나의 용사여,
Now my champion,
오늘 밤은 푹 쉬게.
rest well this night,
내일이면 그대는
for tomorrow you sail for the Kingdom
대거폴 왕국으로 항해할 테니!
of Daggerfall !